Hassan ALI



Contact

Address:

House#175/C Allama Iqbal colony, Faisalabad Pakistan. **Phone:**

- +923076055453
- +923416055461

Email:

thehassanali98@gmail.com

Nationality:

Pakistani.

Passport number:

US1822551

<u>Languages</u>

English- Fluent in Speaking, Reading, Writing. Urdu- Fluent in Speaking, Reading, Writing.

Summary

A strong collaborator and creative problem solver who possess ademonstrated background intheimplementation and maintenance of networks. I have hands onand detail- oriented approach to ensuring the smooth operation of communication networks. I am expert at anticipating and mitigating potential failures, and extensive experience of route analysis, faultisolation. Possessing excellent client facing skills and superb attention to details means that I can follow complex technical instructions to not only troubleshoot problems but also keep end users happy. I got training from someone who always has a professional and well-groomed appearance.

Skill Highlights

- Identifying, diagnosing, and resolving network problems.
- Monitoring network performance.
- Performing implementation and maintenance tasks on the LAN and WAN.
- Proactive in assessing and making recommendations for improvement.
- Willing to travel based on assigned project demands.
- Accurate documentation skills.
- Comprehensive knowledge of networkingconcepts.
- Coordinating upgrade schedules.
- Evaluatingnew software and hardwaretechnologies.

♦ Personal:

- Listening actively and carefully to the opinions and ideas of others.
- Dealing effectively with highly stressful situations.
 - Maintaining knowledge of emerging networking. technologies.
 - Able to drive results with a sense of urgencyrelative to the end user.

Education

- ➤ BS Information technology:— University of Education Lahore, Pakistan.(2017-2021).
 - With 3.33 CGPA.
- > ICS: Post graduate college of science, Samanabad Faisalabad. (2015-2017).
 - With 73.2 %
- ➤ **Matric:** Govt. Johar public high school. Faisalabad. (2013-2015).
 - With 80.8 %

Experience:

- IT officer at Beacon Impex Private Limited / MTM Faisalabad. (2021-Present)
 - Manage and configure network switches.
 - Troubleshooting in network.
 - Monitoring antivirus server (Eset, Symantec).
 - Manage Firewalls.
 - Domain controller, File server.
 - Handel DNS, Active Directory Server, VMware installation & ESXi os troubleshooting.
 - Provide backup support for the Network Infrastructure Engineer as needed
 - Keep up-to-date with the latest developments in IT systems, security, and automotive technologies, and propose innovative solutions to enhance our IT infrastructure
 - Monitoring & reporting the health status of all IT hardware, internet (Routers), and network devices.
- Umer Faizan Enterprises (2020-2021)
 - Windows Server 2000,2003,2008,2012,2016,2019,2022 Installation and configuration.
 - Installation hardware and software's & All Drivers, Windows installation.
 - Install, configure, and maintain server systems, storage devices, andrelated hardware and software components.
 - **Networking**: Hands on training with real world networking devices from Saylani massIT training institute. (2020)
- Internee, Govt. Laboratory school samanabad Faisalabad. (2020)
 - α. Handled classes dealing with basic computer, keyboard, and Internet etc.
 - β. Managed to supervise students' lab work and guided them
 - χ. Maintained student attendance records, grades, and other required records.

Trainings

- Google IT Support
- > MCSA
- > CCNP

Certifications

- Cisco certified network associate (CCNA) 200-301.
 - ♦ Faisalabad Pearson VUE.
- Microsoft Certified Azure fundamental (AZ-900)

◆ Faisalabad Pearson VUE.